Guide to the Dorothea Thomas Lynch papers, 1936-1979
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Dorothea Thomas Lynch papers
Bulk, 1936-1940
1936-1979
C0242
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
2.0 linear feet (3 boxes)
The Dorothea Thomas Lynch papers contains correspondence, issues of the Federal Theatre bulletin, issues of the Federal Theatre in the South, production notes, scripts, and set designs for the production The Girl of the Golden West, class outlines for the History of drama, newsclippings about the Florida Federal Theatre Project, and scrapbooks containing programs, photographs, and newsclippings about Jacksonville, Miami, and Tampa, Florida Federal Theatre Project productions.
Lynch, Dorothea Thomas
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Dorothea Thomas Lynch on March 14, 1977.
Biographical note
Dorothea Thomas Lynch was the State Director of the Federal Theatre Project in Florida. Before joining the FTP she worked for eight years as the Head of the Rollins College dramatic department.
The Federal Theatre Project was a division of the Works Progress Administration (WPA), which provided employment for large numbers of artists, writers, and performers during the Great Depression (1929-1939). The Federal Theatre began in 1935 and, until its end in 1939, flourished as the first and only federally sponsored and subsidized theater program in the United States. Directed by Hallie Flanagan (1880-1969), it was a way for theatrical professionals to gain employment during the Depression.
Scope and Content
The Dorothea Thomas Lynch papers contains correspondence, issues of the Federal Theatre bulletin, issues of the Federal Theatre in the South, production notes, scripts, and set designs for the production The Girl of the Golden West, class outlines for the History of drama, newsclippings about the Florida Federal Theatre Project, and scrapbooks containing programs, photographs, and newsclippings about Jacksonville, Miami, and Tampa, Florida Federal Theatre Project productions.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically with oversize materials at the end.
Related Material
The Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, the Federal Theatre Project collection, the Federal Theatre Project photograph collection, as well as numerous other personal papers.
Index Terms
Persons:
Lynch, Dorothea Thomas.
Corporate Names:
Federal Theatre Project (U.S.)
Subjects:
Actors--Photographs.; New Deal, 1933-1939.; Performing arts.; Theater--United States.
Document Types
Scrapbooks.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Includes correspondence between Lynch and Hallie Flanagan.
- Correspondence between Lynch and Robert F. Mardis, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Federal Theatre bulletin (It Can't Happen Here) (vol. 2 no. 2), circa 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Federal Theatre bulletin (National Policy Board Agenda), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Federal Theatre Project in general, 1936-1939 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Federal Theatre in the South (vol. 1, no. 1), June 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Federal Theatre in the South (vol. 1, no. 2), October 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Florida Federal Theatre Project, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- The Girl of the Golden West production notebook, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The Girl of the Golden West script and set designs, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The Girl of the Golden West script with annotations, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- History of the drama, class outlines, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- History of the drama, class outlines, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- If Ye Break Faith, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Correspondence and general information, photocopies.
- Miles Gloriousus script and set design, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Newsclippings, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photographs: copy negatives of Ninth Guest, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Twelfth Night production notebook, March 1937 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Uncle Tom's Cabin script, April 1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Scrapbook, 1936-1939 (Box 2)
  Programs, photographs, and clippings from Jacksonville productions. Includes programs and photographs of "Animated History of Drama" series performed by Florida State Touring CO. Music and synopsis of If Ye Break Faith. Biography of playwritght Maria Coxe. Clippings and correspondence on termination of the FTP.
- Scrapbook, 1936-1939 (Box 3)
  Programs, photographs, newspaper clippings about the Miami and Tampa, Florida Federal Theatre. Some material in Spanish.